Jagan Pazhaniyandi

Software Engineering Manager

20+ years of experience in Consulting & Engineering Manager for various companies across the technology landscape in Digital Transformation, Modernization, Infrastructure Modernization, Customer Experience. Over the years have worked across different streams - Tech Leading, Design & Development, Solution Analyst, Product Management, Enterprise & Application Architecture in an Onsite-Offshore Delivery Model, Agile/Safe Agile Mode for a variety of products and applications.

jagan.pazhaniyandi@gmail.co m

3109104447

Dallas, TX

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaganpazhaniyandi/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Beyond

Software Engineering Manager

Dallas, Texas | June 2022 - current

- Managed three teams in Beyond, achieving a **20% improvement in customer satisfaction** by optimizing warehouse and return systems
- Led application development and support for U.S. Fulfillment Centers, centralizing operations and ensuring the daily handling of 1,000 orders with increased efficiency
- Delivered **\$560K annual savings** by implementing an in-house liquidator onboarding process, reducing warehouse labor and shipping costs
- Managing the Reverse Logistics Projects to support \$500M Covering all of USA
- Reengineered warranty processes saving \$350K and enhanced warranty shopping experience, reduced resolution time by 10 hours, and improved efficiency by 17%
- Engineered onboarding workflows for Angi and streamlining the installation process to boost conversion rates and enhance the customer experience, driving a \$3.4 million contribution margin
- Transitioned to a generative AI Platform for chatbot and SMS reducing support tickets by 30% and boosting satisfaction rates
- Built Various Projects with Overstock's transition to Bed Bath and Beyond ensuring smooth operations and 100% business continuity

Argano Keste

Senior Technology Consultant

Dallas, Texas | May 2013 - June 2022

- Led 15+ client implementations across diverse industries (Symantec, Thermo Fisher, Western Union) in an consulting environment. Gained experience working with a wide range of technologies
- Converted business goals into features for SAFe Agile, driving preplanning, socialization, and deep dives. Enhanced business alignment through 3+ PI Planning cycles
- Reduced delays by 80% by implementing a payment guideline validation engine

SKILLS

Leadership & Management:

- Technical Leadership, Strategic Planning, Agile/Safe Agile Methodologies
- Stakeholder & Client Relationship Management, Team Building & Mentoring
- Technical Analysis & Application design
- User Story Grooming, planning sessions and prioritize development stories among teams.

Specialized Knowledge

- Microservices Architecture
- Warehouse Management Systems WMS (HighJump/Körber), Bartender, Transportation Management Systems TMS (Blujay), Reverse Logistics
- Work with Ui/UX Teams to define User Interfaces that are aligned with Business Visions

Technical Expertise

- Cloud Platforms: AWS (Lambda, API Gateway, ECS, DynamoDB, EC2), GCP
- Programming & Frameworks: Java, Spring Boot, REST APIs, Oracle ADF/WebCenter, Angular, Node.js, React, Next.js

- Designed a centralized Single Entity Store at Western Union, optimizing payment processing costs and faster payments to end users
- Streamlined bank data services with the 'Find a Bank' microservice, cutting development hours by 40%
- Led the upgrade of *Enterprise Products*' entire suite of Oracle products from 11g to 12c version as Delivery Manager/Technical Lead
- Led the implementation of the Oracle Coherence Cache enabling all applications to access location, customer, and equipment data. This integration resulted in a **4x improvement in performance**
- Led the development of a web application for *Thermo Fisher* using Oracle Middleware stack that supported 2,000 users at launch, enabling tailored views, secure dashboards, and global inventory reports
- Designed and developed Portal and Content Server for Enterprise Products, providing a centralized platform for 8,000 employees across all departments to collaborate and access critical content
- Developed Portal for Schreiber, enabling internal teams to collaborate, publish blogs, discussions, and announcements, enhancing communication and knowledge sharing across the organization
- Created a single destination Oracle Webcenter portal for Symantec, enabling seamless navigation across enterprise services

- Database: Oracle DB, MySql, Postgres, DynamoDB, MongoDb
- DevOps Tools: Jenkins, Maven, SonarQube, Checkmarx
- Enterprise Tools: Oracle
 ADF, Webcenter Portal,
 Content Servers, WebLogic,
 Oracle Coherence Cache,
 Redis Cache, Kafka,
 Pulsar,RabbitMQ,
 ElasticSearch, REST
 services, GraphQL
- Warehouse Management Systems-HighJump/Körber, Blujay/Parcel/E2Open Transportation Management Systems TMS Systems, Bartender, Rebus

Cognizant Technology Solutions

Senior Associate Consultant

June 2004 - May 2013

- Orchestrated the migration of custom application suites to Oracle Ecosystem, serving as a pivotal liaison among Datawarehousing, QA, and Development teams . Led a team of 20 members in onsite-offshore
- Design & Developed a Visibility Tool for business to track shipments. The tool enhanced visibility and resulted in significant improvements in the shipment tracking process
- Design and Developed portal for BP & GM that allowed Schneider to request Inbound Transportation of their supplier base. This application managed various EDI Workflows provided purchase order visibility
- Identified root cause analysis for support tickets to identity potential fixes resulting in cost savings and faster efficiency of warehouse processes
- Maintained 6 High Jump warehouses for companies such as Wal-Mart, Kohls, Target & Family Dollar and established a production support model for applications handling warehouse management
- Led a team of 6 in creating a Pricing app that captures, processes, and responds to custom requests for quotes. This tool was used to price the North American market

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering Information Technology

PSG College of Technology 2000 - 2004 India

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate
- AWS Certified Developer Associate
- Oracle Application
 Development Framework
 11g Certified
 Implementation Specialist